Saints and Soldiers: Airborne Creed is a war, drama,
action film directed by Ryan Little.
On August 15, 1944 the 517th Parachute Regimental Combat
Team (PRCT) jumped over the south of France.
Their mission was to support and protect the Allied Troops marching to Berlin.
Landing in enemy territory, they fell under immediate attack.
In their effort to complete the mission and rendez-vous with their unit, three isolated
paratroopers come across a group of French resistants in desperate need.
They decide to help liberate some of the captive Partisans.
Doing so they will risk their lives.
Corporal James Rossi, played by Corbin Allred.
Sergeant Caleb Jones, played by David Nibley.
Corporal Harland 'Bud' Curtis, played by Jasen Wade.
Emilie, played by Virginie Fourtina Anderson.
Erich Neumann, played by Lincoln Hoppe.
Charlotte, played by Nichelle Aiden.
Saints and Soldiers: Airborne Creed is a 2012 war drama film directed
by Ryan Little and produced by Little and Adam Abel.
It is the second installment in the Saints and Soldiers film series, and is based on
events that took place during the invasion of Southern France in World War II.
The film stars Corbin Allred, David Nibley, and Jasen Wade.
The film was shot in Utah, on a tight budget, saving money by using
volunteer World War II reenactors as some of the actors and extras.
The film received mixed reviews; many critics found the film mediocre,
yet still praised the performances and cinematography.
The film explores themes of world war ii, us army, family
relationships, u.s. soldier, mormon missionary.
The tone is emotional.